<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arbaz Hussain - blog</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 19:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 19:02:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skiing Adventure at Shymbulak,KZ guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This winter, I finally decided to fulfill a long-held dream of learning to ski. I packed my bags and headed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://shymbulak.com/&quot;&gt;Shymbulak Ski Resort in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, a place renowned for its stunning slopes and breathtaking views. As I stood at the top of the mountain, feeling the crisp air against my face, I couldn’t help but think of Jean-Claude Killy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1965, a young Killy stood on a similar snow-covered peak in the French Alps, facing the challenge ahead with determination. His journey from that moment led him to become one of the greatest skiers of all time, winning three gold medals at the 1968 Winter Olympics. Killy’s story, like many others, is a testament to the enduring spirit of skiing—a sport that challenges the body, mind, and soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://welcome.kz/en/assets/images/products/0_gallery/locations/almaty/shymbulak.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Shymbulak Ski Resort&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-shymbulak&quot;&gt;Why Shymbulak?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-unique-destination&quot;&gt;A Unique Destination&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan might not be the first place that comes to mind for a winter sports holiday, but Shymbulak Ski Resort in Almaty offers a unique and unforgettable skiing experience. The resort is the biggest and most modern in Central Asia, boasting a diverse set of slopes suitable for skiers and snowboarders of all levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the appealing aspects of Shymbulak is its affordability compared to more famous ski resorts in Europe or North America. Additionally, it’s easily accessible from Almaty, with public transport options making the journey straightforward and convenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winter sports season in Almaty usually starts from late November or early December and continues until late March, depending on the season and the snowfall. The high altitude ensures the slopes retain their snow well throughout the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-to-shymbulak&quot;&gt;Getting to Shymbulak&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;by-public-transport&quot;&gt;By Public Transport&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Almaty, take bus 12 from Dostyk Avenue (Dostyk Plaza or Hotel Kazakhstan stops). This bus takes you to Medeu, the highest ice skating rink in the world, in about 30 minutes. Get off one stop before the bus terminal at Medeu to find the cable car station across the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;by-taxi&quot;&gt;By Taxi&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A taxi ride from Almaty to Medeu costs around 2000 tenge (a bit more than $5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cable-car&quot;&gt;Cable Car&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purchase a day pass for the cable car to reach the ski resort. Options include a round-trip ticket for 2500 tenge (adult)/1500 tenge (kid) or a combi-pass for 3500 tenge (adult)/2500 tenge (kid) that includes all three cable cars up to the highest point of the resort at 3200 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ski-pass-and-equipment-rental&quot;&gt;Ski Pass and Equipment Rental&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ski-passes&quot;&gt;Ski Passes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekdays&lt;/strong&gt;: 6500 tenge (adults)/3000 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekends&lt;/strong&gt;: 9500 tenge (adults)/4500 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night skiing (Thursdays and Saturdays)&lt;/strong&gt;: 5500 tenge (adults)/2500 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Season pass&lt;/strong&gt;: 300,000 tenge (adult), 220,000 tenge (youth 11-23 y.), 150,000 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;equipment-rental&quot;&gt;Equipment Rental&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rental costs range from 5000 to 9000 tenge per day, depending on the equipment needed. Bring your passport for identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lockers&quot;&gt;Lockers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rent a locker at the base of the resort for 1000 tenge per day, 3500 tenge for a week, 12,500 tenge for a month, or 48,000 tenge for the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skisnowboarding-classes&quot;&gt;Ski/Snowboarding Classes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual classes start from 13,500 tenge for 1.5 hours. A package of 10 classes costs 75,000 tenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;slope-difficulty-levels&quot;&gt;Slope Difficulty Levels&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 20 km of slopes available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beginner&lt;/strong&gt;: 4 km&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermediate&lt;/strong&gt;: 10 km&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced&lt;/strong&gt;: 6 km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start early to finish your hike before dark, as the mountains lack lighting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;standing-up-and-finding-your-balance&quot;&gt;Standing Up and Finding Your Balance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing up on skis can be daunting, especially on a slope. But like Killy, every great skier starts somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;[Standing Up on Skis]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UWc7k5bUmRs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/UWc7k5bUmRs/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing Up on Skis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Up&lt;/strong&gt;: Rotate your body perpendicular to the slope to find stability. Use your sticks for support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walk in a Semicircle&lt;/strong&gt;: Position yourself correctly by walking in a semicircle if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your stance is crucial in skiing. Lean forward, adopting a slight squat position with your ankles flexed. Your body should form a shape like a forward slash () or an open angle (&amp;lt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mastering-basic-techniques&quot;&gt;Mastering Basic Techniques&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation of skiing lies in mastering basic techniques. These fundamentals will serve as your bedrock as you progress to more advanced maneuvers.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;[Skiing Basics]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snowplow&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the first techniques you’ll learn is the snowplow. By positioning your skis in a wide V shape (similar to jumping jack openings), you control your speed and maintain balance. This technique is vital for beginners to build confidence on the slopes.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrWL_sO2ox0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/vrWL_sO2ox0/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Snowplow Position&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snowplow Technique&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jumping&lt;/strong&gt;: Practice small jumps to get comfortable with the sensation of leaving the ground and landing back on your skis. This will help you navigate bumps and uneven terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;turning-and-carving&quot;&gt;Turning and Carving&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning and carving are essential skills that allow you to navigate the slopes with grace and precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_yfFGDuJ2g0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/_yfFGDuJ2g0/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Turning and Carving&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;[Turning and Carving]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turning&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Turn by putting more weight on one ski and slightly turning your feet. The ski should be slightly edgy, lifting on one side to facilitate the turn.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carving&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel Turns&lt;/strong&gt;: Practice parallel turns to carve through the snow with more control.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J-Turn Practice&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage in J-turn practices to perfect your carving technique.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personal-reflections-a-day-on-the-slopes&quot;&gt;Personal Reflections: A Day on the Slopes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time at Shymbulak, I had the pleasure of meeting a group of seasoned skiers who graciously took me under their wing. Watching them effortlessly glide down the mountain, I realized that skiing was as much about technique as it was about embracing the moment. Each fall was a lesson, each turn a victory. The camaraderie and shared passion for the sport were palpable, making every run down the slope a shared celebration of triumph and perseverance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-takeaways&quot;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always ensure your ski gear is ready and well-maintained.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean your boots before stepping into your skis for a secure fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;basic-techniques&quot;&gt;Basic Techniques:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master the snowplow for speed control and stability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice jumping to handle varied terrain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;advanced-skills&quot;&gt;Advanced Skills:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfect your turning by focusing on weight distribution and edging.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage in carving through parallel turns and J-turn practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skiing at Shymbulak was more than just a winter getaway; it was a journey of self-discovery and a test of resilience. As I glided (and sometimes stumbled) down the slopes, I realized that skiing is a lot like life. There are highs and lows, triumphs and setbacks, but what really matters is the determination to keep going. The breathtaking views of the Tien Shan Mountains and the exhilarating rush of speeding down the slopes reminded me that every challenge we face is an opportunity to grow and to find joy in the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re an experienced skier or a beginner like me, Shymbulak offers an adventure that’s both thrilling and enriching. So, pack your bags, embrace the adventure, and remember: it’s not about how many times you fall, but how many times you get back up. Happy skiing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UWc7k5bUmRs&amp;amp;list=PL3K6zYQwjtqVJC9pvdn3xEceWHaYtG_J5&amp;amp;index=2&quot;&gt;Standing Up on Skis&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OcLEgI_vtZQ&quot;&gt;Skiing Basics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrWL_sO2ox0&quot;&gt;Snowplow Technique&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_yfFGDuJ2g0&quot;&gt;Turning and Carving&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/skii</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/skii</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Breaking Free from Expectations Changed My Life?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only true wisdom is in knowing you know nothing.”&lt;/em&gt; - Socrates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In ancient Greece, a man named Socrates roamed the streets of Athens, engaging in conversations that challenged the very foundations of societal norms and expectations. His relentless questioning led him to the understanding that true wisdom comes from recognizing one’s own ignorance. This profound insight resonates deeply with my own journey of breaking free from predefined boundaries and societal expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, as I sat alone, contemplating the rigid confines of my life, I reflected on the transformative experiences I had while traveling. Each journey exposed me to diverse perspectives and ideas, breaking me out of my bubble. Meeting countless people from different walks of life, I began to question everything and embrace uncertainty. These encounters sparked a flame within me, making me realize that the walls I had built around myself were not real—they were constructs of my own making, influenced by societal norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-crisis-of-existence&quot;&gt;The Crisis of Existence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-descent-into-meaninglessness&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Descent into Meaninglessness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking free from societal expectations led me into an existential crisis. As I questioned the meaning of life, I found myself grappling with the realization that life, in itself, is inherently meaningless. This thought was both liberating and terrifying. Without a predefined purpose, everything seemed futile. I felt lost and demotivated, as if I were adrift in an endless sea without a compass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Man is condemned to be free; because once thrown into the world, he is responsible for everything he does.”&lt;/em&gt; - Jean-Paul Sartre&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sartre’s words echoed in my mind, emphasizing the burden of freedom. Without external guidance, I was responsible for creating my own meaning. This newfound freedom felt like a heavy weight, dragging me down into a spiral of despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-path-to-self-creation&quot;&gt;The Path to Self-Creation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;embracing-self-awareness&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embracing Self-Awareness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the depths of my crisis, I stumbled upon the concept of self-awareness. I began documenting my thoughts and feelings daily, practicing mindfulness, and reflecting on my actions. This process of self-examination allowed me to understand that purpose and passion are not prebuilt constructs; they are created through our actions and choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The unexamined life is not worth living.”&lt;/em&gt; - Socrates&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote became my mantra as I delved deeper into self-awareness. I realized that true fulfillment comes from within, not from external validation or societal expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-my-own-path&quot;&gt;Creating My Own Path&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this newfound understanding, I started to carve out a path that was uniquely mine. I set goals that resonated with my values and passions, focusing on activities that brought me joy and fulfillment. This approach led to a sense of ownership and pride in my achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dedicated myself to constant physical improvement, recognizing the importance of maintaining a healthy body to support a healthy mind. I also pursued various forms of freedom—psychological, financial, economic, and social. These goals were not just end destinations but part of a never-ending process of growth and self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is not in the stars to hold our destiny but in ourselves.”&lt;/em&gt; - William Shakespeare&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shakespeare’s words reminded me that I am the architect of my own destiny. By setting my own goals and creating a life that aligns with my values, I found a sense of purpose and direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-process-and-fulfillment&quot;&gt;The Power of Process and Fulfillment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;falling-in-love-with-the-journey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Falling in Love with the Journey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continued on this path, I discovered the secret to consistency: the power of awareness of the values my goals would bring. By focusing on the process rather than the outcome, I found joy in the journey itself. Each step forward, no matter how small, brought a sense of accomplishment and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Success is not the key to happiness. Happiness is the key to success. If you love what you are doing, you will be successful.”&lt;/em&gt; - Albert Schweitzer&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schweitzer’s insight perfectly encapsulated my experience. By loving the process and finding happiness in the present moment, I was able to maintain my motivation and stay on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-takeaways&quot;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questioning Societal Expectations&lt;/strong&gt;: Breaking free from predefined boundaries can lead to an existential crisis, but it is a necessary step towards self-discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating Your Own Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Purpose and passion are not prebuilt; they are created through our actions and choices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: Practicing self-awareness and mindfulness helps in understanding one’s true desires and values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Joy of the Process&lt;/strong&gt;: Focusing on the journey rather than the outcome brings fulfillment and motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Growth&lt;/strong&gt;: Constantly setting and pursuing personal goals leads to a sense of purpose and direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my journey from predefined boundaries to a life of freedom and self-creation, I have learned that true fulfillment comes from within. By questioning societal expectations and embracing self-awareness, I found a path that is uniquely mine. The process of growth and self-discovery is never-ending, and I am grateful for the sense of purpose and fulfillment it brings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only limit to our realization of tomorrow is our doubts of today.”&lt;/em&gt; - Franklin D. Roosevelt&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt’s words remind us that the only barriers to our future success are the doubts we hold today. By embracing our freedom and creating our own path, we can overcome these doubts and achieve true fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean-Paul_Sartre&quot;&gt;Jean-Paul Sartre - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socrates&quot;&gt;Socrates - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Shakespeare&quot;&gt;William Shakespeare - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Schweitzer&quot;&gt;Albert Schweitzer - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franklin_D._Roosevelt&quot;&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/freedom</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/freedom</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>perspective</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why do i listen to the music?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Without music, life would be a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;― Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my last trip to Himachal, I got involved in a massive argument about playing loud music in public. One of my friends shared their perspective on the kind of music I was listening to, questioning why it had no lyrics, no classical instruments, and was mostly beats and electronic sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They argued that it wasn’t real music and expressed disappointment in how Gen Z isn’t listening to what they consider actual music but instead to these types of sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event made me think more about my relationship with the type of music I’m listening to and helped me understand it more deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a philosophical perspective, music is a reflection of the human condition. Nietzsche’s assertion, &lt;strong&gt;“Without music, life would be a mistake”&lt;/strong&gt; resonates deeply with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music, in its various forms, becomes a mirror reflecting our innermost thoughts, emotions, and existential quests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sounds confusing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain it more deeply and also to dive into my personal relationship history with music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;memories-and-emotions&quot;&gt;Memories and Emotions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt that a certain type of music can trigger memories from the past, evoking nostalgic moments? I’m sure everyone has experienced this at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been deep in problem-solving mode, totally focused, and then suddenly you notice the crazy intense music playing in the background? You’re like, &lt;em&gt;“Wow, this is awesome, I need to add this to my playlist”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that national anthems and patriotic songs can make us feel a deep sense of pride and loyalty to our country. At the same time, devotional songs can lift you up spiritually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But have you ever wondered why these songs evoke such strong emotions?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What makes them so special that they can trigger these feelings?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These moments, deeply embedded in our memories, reveal the timeless and universal power of music to touch our hearts and souls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-awakening&quot;&gt;The Awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, my taste in music was pretty basic. I loved classical Bollywood hits, Top chart songs, and Chill lo-fi tunes, all in my own little bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I avoided anything too intense because it usually gave me headaches or just didn’t resonate with me and that was totally fine by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, over time, diving deep into philosophical questions, experiencing different perspectives, traveling a lot, hanging out with friends who listen to diverse genres of music, and trying new experiences opened my senses to a new dimension of sound. Over the period, I could feel the energy and emotion behind every note and rhythm, &lt;strong&gt;that’s when I truly connected with music.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music, at that moment, became more than just sound. It was an experience, a way to connect with myself and express our unspoken emotions. It didn’t need words or traditional instruments, it was powerful in its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shift led me to understand the diverse meanings and creations of music, allowing me to use it as a personal tool for various aspects of my life : be it &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;self discovery, workouts, focus, or mood management&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philosophers have long contemplated the role of music in human life. Nietzsche, who famously declared that “Without music, life would be a mistake” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:nietzsche&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:nietzsche&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; saw music as an essential force that connected us to our deepest emotions and highest aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nietzsche believed that music had the power to transcend the mundane, allowing us to tap into a more profound sense of purpose and potential.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I started using music for my personal growth. It helps me stay consistent with workouts, push my limits, face fears and challenges, and connect deeply with myself. I’ll dive into this more in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The philosopher Arthur Schopenhauer &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:schopenhauer&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:schopenhauer&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; also spoke of music as a universal language that could convey the essence of life’s struggles and triumphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For Schopenhauer&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:schopenhauer:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:schopenhauer&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, music was a direct expression of the world’s will , a force that drives all existence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Through music, we encounter this will and, in turn, are inspired to push beyond our limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-experience&quot;&gt;Personal Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have been listening to music extensively for the last 2 years. Some of the major things I’ve noticed are:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose Fuel&lt;/strong&gt;: Music reignites the passion, it’s an tool to keep my desires burning bright and acts as a constant reminder of my goals, pushing me forward when the path gets tough.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Existential Awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: There’s a unique sensation of being truly alive when you’re lost in music. It heightens your awareness of the present moment, making you feel connected to your existence in a profound way.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soul Healer&lt;/strong&gt;: Music has an almost magical ability to mend my soul. It reaches depths that words often can’t, providing solace and comfort during the hardest times.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Booster&lt;/strong&gt;: Whenever feeling drained, using music as your recharge button. A powerful beat or a soothing melody to rejuvenate the spirit, giving me the strength to carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mood Magic&lt;/strong&gt;: music works is like a switch that can instantly change your emotional state. Whether you need a boost of energy, a moment of calm, or a surge of inspiration, the right tune can transport you there.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I’ve noticed that when you start linking music to your experiences, the magic really starts to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have those nostalgic moments with songs that remind us of the past. But things get even more interesting when music becomes tied to a long-term goal or process you’re working on. &lt;em&gt;That music then becomes part of your journey towards achieving that goal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Instance, I began playing the same kind of music I loved, over and over, for specific situations, like my workouts at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There was this one DJ’s concert on YouTube that I always played. Usually, I’d get bored of a song if I overplayed it, but this time was different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more I listened, the deeper my connection with that music grew.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I ended up playing the same 1-hour-and-30-minute concert for my entire gym sessions &lt;strong&gt;throughout the year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now, listening to the same music again during your low points triggers that state of mind to push forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that the music became linked to my workout routines, helping me hit my targets and making the overall experience more intense, meaningful and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For instance, when doing self-discovery, journaling , brainstorming or developing new ideas, I turn to Hozho’s &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSNcXegRhcE&quot;&gt;DJ Mix 03 (Live @ Jardins Efémeros, Viseu)&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;. This melodic dark music inspires me and &lt;strong&gt;helps me channel my desires into actionable plans.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music speaks to our inner selves, tapping into what makes life meaningful. It pushes us to make every moment count, urging to strive harder, push past boundaries, and achieve what once thought was impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The beats, lyrics, and rhythms resonated with something deep within me, pushing me to keep going, to push harder, to test and eventually break my limits.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In his philosophy, Nietzsche&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:nietzsche:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:nietzsche&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; often emphasized the importance of embracing life in all its complexity, including its joys and sufferings.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Music, with its ability to evoke and transform emotions, serves as a powerful tool for this embrace. It allows us to feel deeply, to connect with others, and to find meaning even in the face of life’s most challenging moments.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1MobY_vR7-g&quot;&gt;Boris Brejcha at Arènes de Nîmes, in France for Cercle&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt; is a minimal techno concert that fuels my workouts. This music pumps me up, turning what could be a monotonous routine into an exhilarating experience. The repetitive beats and &lt;strong&gt;intense energy make me feel like I’m dancing in a club rather than exercising in a gym.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Every day in the gym, I play this kind of music for the whole past year and visualize myself hiking, running over stones, reaching the top, dancing, and vibing to the music.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When I feel the music during a hike, it’s like a rush of inspiration and euphoria. It makes me feel truly alive and aware of my own existence, and it fills me with pride for all the effort I’ve put in to get there.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This music always reminds me to get out of the comfort zone, that’s exactly where I rediscovered myself, that’s after all, I am capable of things I thought I didn’t have in me.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RvRhUHTV_8k&quot;&gt;Ben Böhmer live above Cappadocia in Turkey for Cercle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a melodic house music set is like a painkiller for me. It relaxes me, keeps me present in the moment, and helps me manifest my desires.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I listen to this music during flow activities that don’t need much effort, like when I’m doing something calm and relaxing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s like finally reaching the top of the mountain you’ve always dreamed of, feeling that pure happiness and peace of mind. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Healing through music is another profound aspect I’ve experienced. Carbon Based Lifeforms’ &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SD6hsVJQtiY?si=cQz1iO9_RS7GBhXJ&quot;&gt;Live at Ozora Festival 2017&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt; is a psy-ambient set that I use to relax and find stillness. The soothing melodies and ambient sounds help calm my mind, reduce stress, and promote a sense of peace.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The concept of music as a healing tool is not new. Throughout history, various cultures have used music to soothe the mind and body.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ancient Greeks, for example, believed in the therapeutic power of music and used it to treat mental and physical ailments.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similarly, indigenous cultures around the world have incorporated music into their healing rituals, recognizing its ability to restore harmony and well-being.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve been using &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Brain.fm&quot;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; music for about a year now, mostly for recharging during work:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Waking up early, doing workouts, handling home stuff, then tackling work and meetings all of this can leave me feeling tired by the afternoon and craving a nap.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I don’t take naps for the recharge, instead, I just lay down on the bed and listen to Brain.fm for 15-20 mins. It helps recharge my energy to start working again.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s been a good alternative to coffee for now :D.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/imgs/inline/spotify.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;spotify&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music, for me, is no longer just about the instruments or the lyrics, it’s about the feelings it evokes.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s about the memories it brings back and the emotions it stirs. Whether it’s the classical symphonies my parents used to play on Sunday mornings or the electronic tracks I now prefer, music has always been a constant companion, reflecting my journey and my growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve been on a musical adventure on Spotify, always on the hunt for new genres, artists, and unique sounds. It’s amazing how discovering fresh tunes can take you on unexpected journeys and open up new horizons. Music really has this incredible ability to change your mood and mindset, don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, When visiting a new place, it can be worthwhile to take in some fresh music and create a lasting memory and emotional association with the location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone also described this to me well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are embedded in the music, as if music and you were one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/imgs/inline/techno.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;found this in dharamkot&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;role-of-music-in-manifestation-and-visualization&quot;&gt;Role of Music in Manifestation and Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manifestation and visualization are powerful techniques that involve using the mind to create and attract desired outcomes. Music can play a significant role in enhancing these practices by creating an emotional and mental state conducive to manifestation. By selecting music that resonates with our goals and desires, we can amplify our intentions and bring them to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, when I visualize achieving a personal goal, I choose music that evokes the emotions associated with that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I’m visualizing success and achievement, I listen to uplifting and triumphant music that fills me with a sense of confidence and empowerment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I’m visualizing relaxation and inner peace, I choose calming and soothing music that fosters a sense of serenity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to using music for manifestation is to select tracks that align with the emotions and mental states you wish to cultivate. By immersing yourself in music that resonates with your intentions, you can create a powerful connection between your mind and your goals, making it easier to manifest your desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always felt a deep connection with music, and I’ve started using it intentionally to alter my brain’s beta waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My plan involves listening to binaural beats and other specialized tracks repeatedly until my brain becomes accustomed to them. Then, I switch to new tracks to further enhance my cognitive abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tools like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brain.fm/&quot;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Spotify’s beta waves playlists are excellent resources for this practice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-science-behind-music-and-the-brain&quot;&gt;The Science Behind Music and the Brain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has shown that listening to music releases dopamine&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Dopamine&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Dopamine&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the neurotransmitter associated with pleasure and reward. This chemical reaction can enhance our mood, increase our motivation, and even reduce the perception of pain. This explains why athletes often rely on high-energy music to boost their performance during training and competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it’s fascinating to note that different types of music can activate different regions of the brain. For example, rhythmic music engages the motor cortex, which is responsible for movement and coordination. On the other hand, melodic and harmonic music stimulates the auditory cortex, which processes sound. This explains why certain types of music can enhance physical performance, while others can promote relaxation and mental clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Binaural beats, in particular, have gained popularity for their ability to influence brainwave patterns&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Binaural&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Binaural&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. These beats consist of two slightly different frequencies played in each ear, creating a perceived third frequency that corresponds to specific brainwave states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, binaural beats in the delta frequency range (1-4 Hz) can induce deep relaxation and sleep, while those in the beta frequency range (13-30 Hz) can enhance focus and concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started using it intentionally to alter my brain’s beta waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My plan involves listening to binaural beats and other specialized tracks repeatedly until my brain becomes accustomed to them. Then, I switch to new tracks to further enhance my cognitive abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brain.fm/&quot;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt; and Spotify’s beta waves playlists are excellent resources for this practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Overstimulation :&lt;/strong&gt; “Anything you consume beyond its threshold will eventually consume you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when my friend criticized my choice in music, it made me realize that everyone’s musical journey is unique. What might seem like noise to one person can be a lifeline to another. And for me, those electronic beats are more than just sounds, they’re a testament to my past, present, and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again, music is a personal choice and depends on the individual.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone may use it one way or another.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The whole purpose of this article is to share my own experience and relationship with music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music, for me, has evolved from being just a source of entertainment to a profound tool for self-exploration and growth. It’s not just about what you hear; it’s about what you feel and how it shapes your journey. So next time you plug in your earphones, think about what you’re really listening to and how it might be shaping your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Music can change the world because it can change people.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Bono&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Bono&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;” - Bono&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hozho. (2021). &lt;strong&gt;DJ Mix 03 (Live @ Jardins Efémeros, Viseu)&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSNcXegRhcE&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brejcha, B. (2020). &lt;strong&gt;Boris Brejcha at Arènes de Nîmes, in France for Cercle&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1MobY_vR7-g&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Böhmer, B. (2021). &lt;strong&gt;Ben Böhmer live above Cappadocia in Turkey for Cercle&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RvRhUHTV_8k&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carbon Based Lifeforms. (2017). &lt;strong&gt;Live at Ozora Festival 2017&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SD6hsVJQtiY?si=cQz1iO9_RS7GBhXJ&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:nietzsche&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Nietzsche, F. (1889). &lt;em&gt;Twilight of the Idols&lt;/em&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/52263&quot;&gt;Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:nietzsche&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:nietzsche:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:schopenhauer&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Schopenhauer, A. (1818). &lt;em&gt;The World as Will and Representation&lt;/em&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/38427&quot;&gt;Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:schopenhauer&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:schopenhauer:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Dopamine&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Research on Music and Dopamine: Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12374491/&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Dopamine&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Binaural&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Research on Binaural Beats: Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28532772/&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Binaural&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Bono&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bono. (1983). &lt;strong&gt;Quote&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/bono_138767&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Bono&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/music</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/music</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>perspective</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
