<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arbaz Hussain - blog</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 18:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 18:52:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Team Mate or Relationship? The Trek That Changed Everything</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I believe every relationship—friendship, companionship, or otherwise—should be built on the foundation of being teammates, working together toward shared goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a story about a girl named Chutki. Funny name, right? It might sound like something out of a kids’ cartoon or a playful nickname, but here’s the twist,she was one of the most thoughtful and sharp people I knew. She could debate philosophy at the drop of a hat and effortlessly turn an awkward moment into something meaningful. She had this way of making me feel both challenged and calm, all at once. We had been friends for a while, sometimes close, sometimes distant, always somewhere in that gray zone where neither of us really knew what we were. Friends? Maybe. Something more? Could be. But we never defined it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story begins on a hike,one of those wild, long treks where every muscle in your body begs you to quit, but something inside you refuses to give in. It was me, Chutki, and a few other friends. The whole idea was to disconnect from the noise of daily life, push our limits, and maybe, just maybe, find some clarity. Little did I know, this hike would completely change how I viewed relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-moment-it-hit-me-partnership-not-heroism&quot;&gt;The Moment It Hit Me: Partnership, Not Heroism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halfway up the trail, Chutki twisted her ankle. Nothing too serious, but enough to slow her down. Naturally, I went into full-on “helpful mode,” hovering around her like an overzealous medic. &lt;strong&gt;“Do you want me to carry your bag?”&lt;/strong&gt; “Should we take a break?” &lt;strong&gt;“Are you sure you’re okay?”&lt;/strong&gt; I asked her a dozen times until she finally gave me a look that could have frozen the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Dude, chill,”&lt;/strong&gt; she said, exasperated. &lt;strong&gt;“I’m fine. You’re stressing me out more than the ankle.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouch. That stung. But more than the sting, it made me stop and think. Why was I being so clingy? Was I genuinely trying to help her, or was I just trying to feel useful? That’s when it hit me,relationships, friendships, whatever you want to call them, aren’t about playing savior. They’re about &lt;strong&gt;partnership&lt;/strong&gt;. About being a teammate, not some knight in shining armor trying to prove something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t my job to carry her through the trek. It was my job to walk beside her, respect her pace, and let her handle things in her own way. That realization? It changed everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fairy-tales-are-overrated-shared-goals-matter&quot;&gt;Fairy Tales Are Overrated: Shared Goals Matter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how growing up, we’re all sold this idea of finding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;“the one”?&lt;/code&gt; That perfect person who will magically complete us and make life feel like a never-ending romantic montage? Yeah, rookie, that’s a load of crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one completes you. You complete yourself. Real relationships aren’t about finding someone to fill the gaps in your life; they’re about finding someone who complements your journey. Someone who’s already whole, just like you, and who’s willing to team up with you to make life a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continued the hike, I started thinking: what if we approached relationships the way we approach a great team project? Shared goals. Mutual effort. Respect for each other’s strengths and weaknesses. No one trying to outshine the other, no one trying to be the hero. Just two people, moving forward together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grow up thinking relationships are built on &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emotions,love, affection, care.&lt;/code&gt; And sure, that stuff is important, but emotions are like weather,they change all the time. One day, you’re head over heels; the next, you’re irritated because they left the toothpaste cap off. What keeps things steady isn’t just love,it’s shared purpose and respect. That’s what makes a relationship more like a solid team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2246/5913/files/we-are-a-team-quotes-6_600x600.jpg?v=1689939933&quot; alt=&quot;love&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;boundaries-make-the-team-work-respect-builds-trust&quot;&gt;Boundaries Make the Team Work: Respect Builds Trust&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that night, after setting up camp, Chutki and I ended up on cooking duty. It wasn’t anything fancy,just instant noodles and soup,but something about the way we worked together felt different. We didn’t need to talk much. There was no need for grand gestures or over-the-top concern,just quiet, steady collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That moment taught me something crucial: &lt;strong&gt;good teammates know how to respect boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;. Earlier in the day, I had crossed a line by hovering over her, thinking I was helping when all I was doing was adding unnecessary pressure. People need space to deal with their stuff. Boundaries aren’t walls meant to keep others out; they’re like well-drawn lines on a map that help everyone navigate without stepping on each other’s toes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boundaries aren’t just about physical space,they’re emotional too. Whether it’s respecting someone’s need for privacy or understanding when they just need to be left alone, boundaries keep things healthy. And here’s a funny thing: respecting boundaries actually brings people closer. It’s like saying, “Hey, I see you, I get you, and I’m here when you need me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t need to hover over Chutki to show I cared. All I needed to do was be there,ready to help if she asked, but respectful enough to let her handle things her way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;intimacy-beyond-the-usual-building-moments-not-drama&quot;&gt;Intimacy Beyond the Usual: Building Moments, Not Drama&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people think intimacy is about grand romantic gestures, constant closeness, or dramatic emotional exchanges. But real intimacy? It’s quieter. It’s about being comfortable in each other’s presence without needing constant validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me and Chutki, intimacy wasn’t about holding hands under the stars or whispering sweet nothings. It was about shared experiences,like boiling water for tea together, laughing over burnt noodles, and sitting in silence by the campfire, staring at the stars. &lt;strong&gt;It’s about building moments that matter, not chasing fleeting emotions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real intimacy isn’t dependent on physical or emotional closeness. It’s about knowing you can share your deepest fears, your weirdest thoughts, and your dumbest jokes without judgment. It’s when someone gets the real you,the messy, unfiltered version,and still wants to stick around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conflict-the-ultimate-test-of-teamwork&quot;&gt;Conflict: The Ultimate Test of Teamwork&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the next morning, Chutki’s ankle was better, and we continued our trek. The trail got steeper, the air thinner, and tempers shorter. At one point, I got a little snappy about the pace. Chutki fired back, and for a moment, it felt like things might spiral into a full-blown argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then she said something that caught me off guard: &lt;strong&gt;“Let’s just focus on getting to the top. We can argue later if it still matters by then.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That shut me up. Not because I didn’t want to argue, but because I realized she was right. &lt;strong&gt;In relationships, conflict is inevitable. What matters is how you handle it.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you escalate things for the sake of winning the argument, or do you step back, cool off, and focus on what really matters?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, as we rested at the summit, we talked it out. No blame, no accusations,just honest conversation. And you know what? That conversation made our bond stronger. Because maturity is realizing that one deep talk and a genuine apology can fix a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mistakes-and-learnings-embrace-dont-fear-mistakes&quot;&gt;Mistakes and Learnings: Embrace, Don’t Fear Mistakes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the final takeaways from the trek, let me talk about something equally important,mistakes. You see, in the corporate world, mistakes are often viewed as costly errors. They waste time, they waste money, and sometimes, they waste both. That’s why companies drill this idea into your head: &lt;strong&gt;“Don’t mess up.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the kicker,your mind starts applying that same logic to personal life, and suddenly, mistakes feel like social disasters. You hesitate to express yourself because, in your head, a mistake will cost you. Except in personal life, the cost isn’t money,it’s missed connections and lost opportunities for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With friends, partners, and family, mistakes are inevitable. The key isn’t avoiding them,it’s learning from them. Say the wrong thing? Apologize, learn, and do better next time. Feel overwhelmed during a trip? Be honest and ask for some space. Here’s how you might handle it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I’m excited to spend time with you, but right now I need some alone time to recharge.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I feel too upset to continue this conversation, so I’d appreciate if we came back to it later.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“If I feel comfortable sharing about that in the future, I’ll definitely let you know.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistakes, when handled with honesty and openness, become lessons that strengthen relationships instead of weakening them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leadership-in-relationships-lead-with-empathy&quot;&gt;Leadership in Relationships: Lead with Empathy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s talk leadership. Not the CEO kind, but the kind that works in relationships. Effective leadership is about stepping up when needed, guiding without controlling, and knowing when to follow instead of lead. Whether it’s planning a trip or navigating a tough conversation, great leadership can build stronger, more respectful partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership isn’t about dominating the relationship,it’s about creating an environment where both people feel empowered to be themselves, make decisions, and grow together. On that trek, I learned that sometimes being a good leader means stepping back and letting someone else take charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-end-of-the-trek-the-start-of-a-new-perspective&quot;&gt;The End of the Trek, The Start of a New Perspective&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we reached the summit, Chutki and I were too tired to talk much. But as we stood there, looking out at the endless horizon, I felt something shift inside me. This wasn’t about romance. It wasn’t about needing someone to make me happy. It was about finding a teammate,someone who could walk with me through life’s toughest climbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way down, I thought about all the times I’d chased relationships in the past, hoping they’d fill some void in my life. But now I knew better. &lt;strong&gt;A real relationship isn’t about finding someone who completes you,it’s about finding someone who complements you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, rookie, next time you find yourself thinking about relationships, forget the fairy tale. Look for someone who’s ready to trek through life’s mountains with you. Someone who shares your goals, respects your space, and knows when to walk beside you in silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because love might light the fire, but it’s teamwork that keeps it burning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://markmanson.net/relationships&quot;&gt;Mark Manson - Relationships&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Author of &lt;em&gt;The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F&lt;/em&gt;ck*, Mark Manson offers no-nonsense relationship advice with a philosophical twist.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/playlists/415/the_secret_to_desire_in_long_te&quot;&gt;TED Talks - Relationship Playlist&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A curated playlist of TED Talks that explore desire, intimacy, and maintaining lasting relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iCvmsMzlF7o&quot;&gt;Brene Brown - The Power of Vulnerability (YouTube)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A must-watch talk on the importance of vulnerability in building meaningful connections.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zenhabits.net/relationship-manifesto/&quot;&gt;Zen Habits - The Relationship Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A minimalist approach to relationships, focusing on simplicity, mindfulness, and emotional awareness.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinybuddha.com/category/blog/love-relationships/&quot;&gt;Tiny Buddha - Relationship Advice&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Personal stories and lessons on love, forgiveness, and building strong partnerships.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/topic/relationships&quot;&gt;Greater Good Magazine - Relationships&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Research-based insights on empathy, gratitude, and the science of love and connection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/trek</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/trek</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>perspective</category>
        
        <category>relationships</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Islamic Finance Meets Blockchain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanna share why Blockchain Decentralised Finance(DeFi) clicks perfectly when combined with Islamic finance, such as :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open-source smart contracts on blockchain ensure transparent and tamper-proof financial agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Protocols offering profit-sharing models instead of interest-based lending, such as liquidity pools where profits are distributed based on participation without earning interest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain finance can feel like an overwhelming beast,an endless maze of protocols, DeFi platforms, and speculative tokens. It’s easy to get lost in the jargon of staking rewards, liquidity pools, and yield farming. But hidden in this chaos lies a golden opportunity: the fusion of &lt;strong&gt;ancient Islamic finance principles&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;modern decentralized blockchain technology&lt;/strong&gt;. This isn’t just another tech trend,it’s a bold new frontier for ethical, transparent, and inclusive finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine riding a camel through a vast desert and finding an oasis where the wisdom of the past meets the technology of the future. That’s what this new world of &lt;strong&gt;Islamic-compliant decentralized finance (DeFi)&lt;/strong&gt; feels like. And at its heart is a set of time-tested principles designed to promote fairness, shared risk, and social good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:1400/0*GGqnJsjPvgj_VHL5&quot; alt=&quot;Islamic Finance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-core-values-of-islamic-finance&quot;&gt;The Core Values of Islamic Finance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Islamic finance, governed by Sharia law, emphasizes five key principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🌍 &lt;strong&gt;Life&lt;/strong&gt; must be respected,so no funding unethical or harmful ventures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🧬 &lt;strong&gt;Reason&lt;/strong&gt; must be protected,investments in industries that harm judgment, like alcohol or gambling, are prohibited.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🤝 &lt;strong&gt;Family&lt;/strong&gt; stability is paramount,practices that exploit individuals or families, like predatory lending, are forbidden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💰 &lt;strong&gt;Wealth&lt;/strong&gt; should serve society,finance should be transparent, ethical, and benefit the broader community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These principles aren’t arbitrary rules,they’re the foundation of a fair and equitable financial system. And this is where blockchain, with its inherent transparency and decentralization, can be a game changer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Finance should serve the people, not enslave them.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-three-pillars-avoiding-riba-maysir-and-gharar&quot;&gt;The Three Pillars: Avoiding Riba, Maysir, and Gharar&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To align with Sharia law, financial activities must avoid three major pitfalls:&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;💸 &lt;strong&gt;Riba (Interest/Usury)&lt;/strong&gt;: 
Charging interest on loans is prohibited because it shifts all the risk to the borrower while the lender profits risk-free. Instead, Islamic finance encourages profit-and-loss sharing. In blockchain terms, this can be achieved through protocols that reward participants based on actual network activity, rather than interest-like mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Imagine a borrower needs $500 for a washing machine. In conventional banking, they would take a loan and owe $600 due to interest.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In Islamic banking, the bank purchases the washing machine for $500, takes ownership, and then sells it to the borrower for $600, payable in installments. &lt;strong&gt;The bank profits from the sale, not interest, and shares real risk by owning the asset.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;🎲 &lt;strong&gt;Maysir (Gambling/Speculation)&lt;/strong&gt;: 
Pure speculation, like betting on the price of a token with no real utility, is forbidden. Tokens that have clear use cases and underlying value,like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/code&gt; as a store of value or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/code&gt; for smart contracts,are more likely to comply with Sharia guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Trading highly speculative memecoins with no intrinsic value is considered haram because it resembles gambling.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, using Ethereum to pay transaction fees or Bitcoin as a store of value is more acceptable because these tokens serve a clear purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;🕵️‍♂️ &lt;strong&gt;Gharar (Excessive Uncertainty)&lt;/strong&gt;: 
Transactions should be transparent and free from ambiguity. Blockchain’s open-source nature and smart contracts can greatly reduce gharar by ensuring all terms are visible and immutable.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: In shady contracts with hidden clauses, gharar is high because one party is unaware of crucial terms. In contrast, a smart contract on Ethereum where all conditions are&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt; publicly verifiable minimizes gharar.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;real-assets-real-value&quot;&gt;Real Assets, Real Value&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Islamic finance emphasizes investments tied to tangible assets. This principle aligns well with asset-backed tokens on the blockchain, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; backed by physical assets like gold or fiat currency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real estate tokens&lt;/strong&gt; representing ownership in actual properties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Wealth is a trust, not a toy.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Consider a token like USDP, backed by gold reserves. Since each token represents a real, tangible asset, it involves less speculation and aligns better with Islamic finance principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach reduces the speculative frenzy that plagues much of the crypto market and creates a more stable and ethical financial environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ethical-banking-vs-defi-a-new-model&quot;&gt;Ethical Banking vs. DeFi: A New Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In traditional Islamic banking, loans aren’t interest-based. Instead, banks and borrowers enter into profit-sharing agreements. Blockchain can replicate this model through decentralized finance platforms where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💼 &lt;strong&gt;Participants pool capital&lt;/strong&gt; to fund projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💳 &lt;strong&gt;Profits are shared&lt;/strong&gt; based on agreed terms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;📈 &lt;strong&gt;Losses are distributed&lt;/strong&gt; fairly, promoting shared risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: In Islamic real estate finance, instead of lending money at interest, the bank and developer form a partnership. The bank provides 60% of the capital, and the developer provides 40%. They jointly own the property and share profits or losses in proportion to their investment. This mirrors the concept of &lt;strong&gt;musharaka&lt;/strong&gt; in Islamic finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in a DeFi real estate project, token holders could collectively own a property and earn rental income, sharing both the gains and risks. This model mirrors the Islamic concept of &lt;strong&gt;musharaka&lt;/strong&gt; (partnership).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Shared risk creates shared responsibility.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;islamic-defi-in-action&quot;&gt;Islamic DeFi in Action&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several blockchain platforms have already received &lt;strong&gt;Sharia-compliant certifications&lt;/strong&gt;, including:&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stellar (XLM)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethereum (ETH)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algorand (ALGO)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These certifications acknowledge that these platforms can support financial activities without violating Islamic principles. In &lt;strong&gt;Islamic-DeFi ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💳 Lending protocols reward participants through transaction fees rather than interest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🔒 Smart contracts ensure transparency and fairness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💰 Tokens represent real economic activities or assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major Islamic scholars have praised these innovations for their potential to democratize finance and bring ethical investment opportunities to more people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-road-ahead-merging-tradition-with-innovation&quot;&gt;The Road Ahead: Merging Tradition with Innovation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As blockchain technology evolves, so does its potential to revolutionize Islamic finance. By combining the ethical foundations of Sharia law with the transparency and inclusiveness of decentralized finance, we can build a financial system that serves everyone,not just the privileged few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where farmers can access funding without falling into debt traps, where developers can partner with banks instead of borrowing at high interest, and where investors can profit ethically by backing real projects. This is the promise of Islamic finance meeting blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be a tech wizard or a financial guru to join this movement. Whether you’re a curious explorer or a seasoned investor, there’s a place for you in this new landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So saddle up, rookie. The desert of traditional finance is vast and dry, but there’s an oasis ahead,one where &lt;strong&gt;Islamic principles and blockchain innovation come together&lt;/strong&gt; to create a future of fair profits, shared risk, and real value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundations of Islamic Finance&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of Sharia-compliant banking. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-World Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt; - Asset-backed tokens and decentralized finance platforms promoting ethical finance. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Islamic Banking Practices&lt;/strong&gt; - Comparison of conventional and Islamic financial models with real-world examples. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharia Compliance in Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; - Reports on Stellar, Ethereum, and Algorand certifications. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/finance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/finance</guid>
        
        <category>finance</category>
        
        <category>perspective</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who’s Got the Monkey?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you keep carrying everyone’s problems, you’ll end up running out of time while they run out of work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you checked out this well-known article?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here’s the link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/1999/11/management-time-whos-got-the-monkey&quot;&gt;Who’s Got the Monkey?
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If not, let me share what I think about it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be real,whether you’re a manager, team leader, or just someone who likes to “help,” chances are you’ve taken on more than your fair share of monkeys. No, not literal monkeys, but those sneaky little things we call &lt;em&gt;problems&lt;/em&gt;. They come in many forms,urgent emails, last-minute tasks, “quick” questions from your team,and before you know it, your day’s derailed, and everyone else is kicking back, waiting for you to solve their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? Yeah, you’re not alone. Let me tell you about Lisa, a customer service manager who learned the hard way that trying to be everyone’s hero just leads to burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lisa-and-the-monkey-problem&quot;&gt;Lisa and the Monkey Problem&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lisa was the kind of manager who wanted to keep her team happy and her customers even happier. Anytime a team member brought her a complaint, she would jump right in, take over the problem, and work on a solution herself. It worked for a while,her team loved her, and things got done. But then, something weird happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lisa noticed she was staying late every night, completely swamped, while her team seemed to be… well, kinda chilling. The more monkeys her team handed her, the less they had to do. Lisa became the bottleneck, and her team stopped taking initiative because, hey, why bother when the boss will handle it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E12AQFnnieLG5uZWQ/article-cover_image-shrink_720_1280/0/1530929749018?e=2147483647&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=lYMNB_ONUZDkigCgVgmp0i_M18_QgOnF2IMtwErm6UQ&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-shift-stop-carrying-the-monkeys&quot;&gt;The Shift: Stop Carrying the Monkeys&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, Lisa had a lightbulb moment. She realized that by taking every problem handed to her, she wasn’t helping,she was hurting both herself and her team. So, she decided to switch things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time Jones, one of her team members, came to her with a customer complaint, instead of saying, “I’ll handle it,” Lisa smiled and said, &lt;strong&gt;“Great. Here’s what we’ll do,why don’t you draft a quick report on the issue, propose a solution, and we’ll review it together?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boom. Monkey returned. Jones walked away, still carrying the problem, but now with clear guidance on what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-manage-monkeys-without-losing-your-mind&quot;&gt;How to Manage Monkeys Without Losing Your Mind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to stop carrying everyone else’s monkeys? Here’s how Lisa turned things around:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spot the Monkey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When someone brings you a problem, ask yourself: &lt;em&gt;Is this my monkey or theirs?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;If it’s not yours, don’t take it.  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hand It Back (Nicely)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Instead of jumping into problem-solving mode, guide them on how to handle it. Use phrases like, &lt;strong&gt;“What do you think we should do?”&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;“Can you draft a plan, and we’ll review it together?”&lt;/strong&gt; This way, you’re helping without taking ownership of the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;
Monkeys thrive on chaos. Don’t let people hand you problems randomly throughout the day. Instead, set up specific times for check-ins or problem-solving meetings. That way, you stay in control, and your team learns to handle things on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-this-works&quot;&gt;Why This Works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lisa’s new approach didn’t just save her time,it empowered her team. By handing monkeys back, she encouraged her team to think for themselves, take responsibility, and only involve her when they really needed to. And guess what? The team got better, faster, and more confident. Lisa finally had time to focus on the big picture instead of firefighting all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-takeaways&quot;&gt;Final Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monkeys = Problems.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let other people’s problems become yours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep the responsibility where it belongs.&lt;/strong&gt; Guide your team, but don’t do their work for them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boundaries matter.&lt;/strong&gt; Set clear processes for when and how issues should be brought to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you keep carrying everyone’s monkeys, you’ll end up exhausted while they kick back. So next time someone tries to hand you a problem, don’t just take it. Help them figure out how to handle it themselves. You’re a leader, not a zookeeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, rookie,stop carrying the monkeys. Start leading the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/1999/11/management-time-whos-got-the-monkey&quot;&gt;Harvard Business Review - Who’s Got the Monkey?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A classic piece on delegation and time management by William Oncken Jr. and Donald L. Wass.*&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leadershipfreak.blog/tag/delegation/&quot;&gt;Leadership Freak - Delegation&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blog with practical tips on delegation and leadership.*&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/topic/leadership&quot;&gt;Greater Good Magazine - Empowering Teams&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Research-based insights on leadership and empowering others.*&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/monkey-management</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/monkey-management</guid>
        
        <category>leadership</category>
        
        <category>delegation</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rape, Silence, and Society’s Shadow</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“He who does not bellow the truth when he knows the truth makes himself the accomplice of liars and forgers.”&lt;/em&gt; - Charles Péguy&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get real for a moment, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;our society is deeply flawed.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world where silence is often more valued than truth, where we’re taught to look the other way instead of confronting the ugly realities around us. Despite the teachings of equal rights in our religion, the reality is that we often fall short. We lean heavily towards a patriarchal structure that subdues women, forcing them into silence to protect family honor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the thing : We don’t have to accept this. You and I, we can be the ones who speak up, who challenge these outdated norms, and who refuse to stay silent when we see injustice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-calculated-gamble-the-perpetrators-philosophy&quot;&gt;The Calculated Gamble: The Perpetrator’s Philosophy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-distortion-of-power-and-confidence&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Distortion of Power and Confidence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drives someone to commit rape, knowing that their victim will live and likely speak out? It’s not just about desire or impulse, there’s a twisted logic at play. Unlike other crimes, where the criminal might believe they can hide their identity or leave no witnesses, rape leaves behind a living testament to the crime. Yet, many rapists act with a disturbing confidence, almost as if they know they’ll get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mindset comes from a deep-seated belief that society will do more to protect the reputation of families and communities than to seek justice for the victim. In many parts of India, a woman’s honor is valued more than her well-being, and this twisted sense of priorities gives rapists the belief that their crime will be met with silence. It’s not reckless, it’s calculated. The real crime here is that our society makes this gamble worth taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-philosophical-burden-of-shame-societys-complicity&quot;&gt;The Philosophical Burden of Shame: Society’s Complicity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-misalignment-of-honor-and-justice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Misalignment of Honor and Justice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shame is a powerful emotion, but in our culture, it’s weaponized against the wrong people. From the moment a girl is born, she faces sexism and oppression so constant that it becomes her norm. She’s taught that her worth is tied to her purity, and that any blemish on this purity is a disgrace not just to her, but to her entire family. This is where our society has really failed,we’ve turned honor into a cage, locking women inside while their oppressors roam free.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When my friend confided in me about her molestation, she wasn’t just talking about the trauma of the assault. She was talking about the crushing weight of shame that followed her, the pressure from her family to keep quiet and move on as if nothing had happened. They weren’t trying to protect her,they were trying to protect themselves from the judgment of others. This is what happens when we let shame dictate our actions: the victim is silenced, and the perpetrator walks free.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But let’s be clear,this isn’t how it has to be. You and I, we’re not going to accept this anymore. We’re going to talk about these issues, loudly and unapologetically. We’re going to call out the people around us,our friends, our family,when they say something racist, sexist, homophobic, or just plain wrong. We’re going to make sure they know it’s not okay. Because things will get better, but only if we make them better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-hypocrisy-of-moral-judgments-gender-and-double-standards&quot;&gt;The Hypocrisy of Moral Judgments: Gender and Double Standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-contradiction-of-equality-and-moral-relativism&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Contradiction of Equality and Moral Relativism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about the double standards we see every day. Our society loves to claim it believes in equality, but when it comes to how we judge men and women, the truth is far from equal. When a man cheats, people might say, “It’s just how men are,” but when a woman does the same, she’s condemned, her character shredded by those who pretend to hold the moral high ground. This isn’t just a cultural problem,it’s a philosophical contradiction that we need to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same goes for how we react to sexual misconduct. When a female teacher is caught having an affair with a male student, you’ll hear guys joking about how lucky the kid is. But if a male teacher does the same to a female student? The outrage is immediate, as it should be. Why the double standard? Why is one case a fantasy and the other a crime? This hypocrisy is ingrained in our society, and it’s up to us to challenge it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-corruption-of-power-arrogance-and-the-illusion-of-immunity&quot;&gt;The Corruption of Power: Arrogance and the Illusion of Immunity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;when-power-becomes-a-shield&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When Power Becomes a Shield&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power is a funny thing,it can do great good, but it can also corrupt. And when it corrupts, it gives people the idea that they’re untouchable. Think about the CEOs, the politicians, the community leaders who abuse their power because they believe they’re above the law. They think their position gives them immunity, that the fear they instill in others will protect them from consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This same mindset applies to rapists who believe they can act with impunity. They count on their victims staying silent, on the shame that society forces upon women to keep their crimes hidden. But here’s the deal,power doesn’t make you immune to justice. It just means the fall is harder when you finally get caught. And we need to make sure these people are caught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-takeaways&quot;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philosophy of Silence&lt;/strong&gt;: The perpetrator’s confidence stems from a societal belief that values reputation over justice, creating an environment where silence is wrongly seen as virtuous.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weaponized Shame&lt;/strong&gt;: Our society has twisted the concept of honor into a tool that protects the oppressor and silences the victim, starting from the moment a girl is born.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral Hypocrisy&lt;/strong&gt;: The double standards in how we judge men and women reveal a deep flaw in our understanding of equality, and it’s up to us to correct it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power and Arrogance&lt;/strong&gt;: Those in positions of power often believe they’re immune to consequences, but we need to hold them accountable, no matter how untouchable they think they are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world where the truth is often hidden behind a veil of silence, but that doesn’t mean we have to accept it. We can tear down this veil by speaking up, by challenging the outdated norms that protect the guilty and silence the innocent. You and I, we’re going to be the ones who refuse to stay quiet. We’re going to call out injustice when we see it, whether it’s racism, sexism, homophobia, or any other form of discrimination. Things will get better,but only if we make them better. The future is in our hands, and it’s up to us to create a society where everyone is held to the same moral standard, where the truth isn’t something to be ashamed of, but something to be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only limit to our realization of tomorrow is our doubts of today.”&lt;/em&gt; - Franklin D. Roosevelt&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt’s words remind us that the only thing holding us back is our own hesitation. By breaking the silence and embracing our power to make change, we can build a future where justice and truth are no longer hidden behind a veil of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Péguy&quot;&gt;Charles Péguy - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franklin_D._Roosevelt&quot;&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/veil-of-silence</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/veil-of-silence</guid>
        
        <category>society</category>
        
        <category>philosophy</category>
        
        <category>injustice</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skiing Adventure at Shymbulak,KZ guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This winter, I finally decided to fulfill a long-held dream of learning to ski. I packed my bags and headed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://shymbulak.com/&quot;&gt;Shymbulak Ski Resort in Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, a place renowned for its stunning slopes and breathtaking views. As I stood at the top of the mountain, feeling the crisp air against my face, I couldn’t help but think of Jean-Claude Killy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1965, a young Killy stood on a similar snow-covered peak in the French Alps, facing the challenge ahead with determination. His journey from that moment led him to become one of the greatest skiers of all time, winning three gold medals at the 1968 Winter Olympics. Killy’s story, like many others, is a testament to the enduring spirit of skiing—a sport that challenges the body, mind, and soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://welcome.kz/en/assets/images/products/0_gallery/locations/almaty/shymbulak.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Shymbulak Ski Resort&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-shymbulak&quot;&gt;Why Shymbulak?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-unique-destination&quot;&gt;A Unique Destination&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan might not be the first place that comes to mind for a winter sports holiday, but Shymbulak Ski Resort in Almaty offers a unique and unforgettable skiing experience. The resort is the biggest and most modern in Central Asia, boasting a diverse set of slopes suitable for skiers and snowboarders of all levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the appealing aspects of Shymbulak is its affordability compared to more famous ski resorts in Europe or North America. Additionally, it’s easily accessible from Almaty, with public transport options making the journey straightforward and convenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winter sports season in Almaty usually starts from late November or early December and continues until late March, depending on the season and the snowfall. The high altitude ensures the slopes retain their snow well throughout the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-to-shymbulak&quot;&gt;Getting to Shymbulak&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;by-public-transport&quot;&gt;By Public Transport&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Almaty, take bus 12 from Dostyk Avenue (Dostyk Plaza or Hotel Kazakhstan stops). This bus takes you to Medeu, the highest ice skating rink in the world, in about 30 minutes. Get off one stop before the bus terminal at Medeu to find the cable car station across the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;by-taxi&quot;&gt;By Taxi&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A taxi ride from Almaty to Medeu costs around 2000 tenge (a bit more than $5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cable-car&quot;&gt;Cable Car&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purchase a day pass for the cable car to reach the ski resort. Options include a round-trip ticket for 2500 tenge (adult)/1500 tenge (kid) or a combi-pass for 3500 tenge (adult)/2500 tenge (kid) that includes all three cable cars up to the highest point of the resort at 3200 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ski-pass-and-equipment-rental&quot;&gt;Ski Pass and Equipment Rental&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ski-passes&quot;&gt;Ski Passes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekdays&lt;/strong&gt;: 6500 tenge (adults)/3000 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekends&lt;/strong&gt;: 9500 tenge (adults)/4500 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night skiing (Thursdays and Saturdays)&lt;/strong&gt;: 5500 tenge (adults)/2500 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Season pass&lt;/strong&gt;: 300,000 tenge (adult), 220,000 tenge (youth 11-23 y.), 150,000 tenge (kids)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;equipment-rental&quot;&gt;Equipment Rental&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rental costs range from 5000 to 9000 tenge per day, depending on the equipment needed. Bring your passport for identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lockers&quot;&gt;Lockers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rent a locker at the base of the resort for 1000 tenge per day, 3500 tenge for a week, 12,500 tenge for a month, or 48,000 tenge for the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;skisnowboarding-classes&quot;&gt;Ski/Snowboarding Classes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual classes start from 13,500 tenge for 1.5 hours. A package of 10 classes costs 75,000 tenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;slope-difficulty-levels&quot;&gt;Slope Difficulty Levels&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 20 km of slopes available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beginner&lt;/strong&gt;: 4 km&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermediate&lt;/strong&gt;: 10 km&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced&lt;/strong&gt;: 6 km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start early to finish your hike before dark, as the mountains lack lighting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;standing-up-and-finding-your-balance&quot;&gt;Standing Up and Finding Your Balance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing up on skis can be daunting, especially on a slope. But like Killy, every great skier starts somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;[Standing Up on Skis]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UWc7k5bUmRs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/UWc7k5bUmRs/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Standing Up on Skis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Up&lt;/strong&gt;: Rotate your body perpendicular to the slope to find stability. Use your sticks for support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walk in a Semicircle&lt;/strong&gt;: Position yourself correctly by walking in a semicircle if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your stance is crucial in skiing. Lean forward, adopting a slight squat position with your ankles flexed. Your body should form a shape like a forward slash () or an open angle (&amp;lt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mastering-basic-techniques&quot;&gt;Mastering Basic Techniques&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The foundation of skiing lies in mastering basic techniques. These fundamentals will serve as your bedrock as you progress to more advanced maneuvers.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;[Skiing Basics]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snowplow&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the first techniques you’ll learn is the snowplow. By positioning your skis in a wide V shape (similar to jumping jack openings), you control your speed and maintain balance. This technique is vital for beginners to build confidence on the slopes.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrWL_sO2ox0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/vrWL_sO2ox0/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Snowplow Position&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Snowplow Technique&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jumping&lt;/strong&gt;: Practice small jumps to get comfortable with the sensation of leaving the ground and landing back on your skis. This will help you navigate bumps and uneven terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;turning-and-carving&quot;&gt;Turning and Carving&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning and carving are essential skills that allow you to navigate the slopes with grace and precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_yfFGDuJ2g0&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.youtube.com/vi/_yfFGDuJ2g0/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Turning and Carving&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;[Turning and Carving]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turning&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Turn by putting more weight on one ski and slightly turning your feet. The ski should be slightly edgy, lifting on one side to facilitate the turn.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carving&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel Turns&lt;/strong&gt;: Practice parallel turns to carve through the snow with more control.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J-Turn Practice&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage in J-turn practices to perfect your carving technique.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personal-reflections-a-day-on-the-slopes&quot;&gt;Personal Reflections: A Day on the Slopes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time at Shymbulak, I had the pleasure of meeting a group of seasoned skiers who graciously took me under their wing. Watching them effortlessly glide down the mountain, I realized that skiing was as much about technique as it was about embracing the moment. Each fall was a lesson, each turn a victory. The camaraderie and shared passion for the sport were palpable, making every run down the slope a shared celebration of triumph and perseverance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-takeaways&quot;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always ensure your ski gear is ready and well-maintained.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean your boots before stepping into your skis for a secure fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;basic-techniques&quot;&gt;Basic Techniques:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master the snowplow for speed control and stability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice jumping to handle varied terrain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;advanced-skills&quot;&gt;Advanced Skills:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perfect your turning by focusing on weight distribution and edging.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage in carving through parallel turns and J-turn practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skiing at Shymbulak was more than just a winter getaway; it was a journey of self-discovery and a test of resilience. As I glided (and sometimes stumbled) down the slopes, I realized that skiing is a lot like life. There are highs and lows, triumphs and setbacks, but what really matters is the determination to keep going. The breathtaking views of the Tien Shan Mountains and the exhilarating rush of speeding down the slopes reminded me that every challenge we face is an opportunity to grow and to find joy in the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re an experienced skier or a beginner like me, Shymbulak offers an adventure that’s both thrilling and enriching. So, pack your bags, embrace the adventure, and remember: it’s not about how many times you fall, but how many times you get back up. Happy skiing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UWc7k5bUmRs&amp;amp;list=PL3K6zYQwjtqVJC9pvdn3xEceWHaYtG_J5&amp;amp;index=2&quot;&gt;Standing Up on Skis&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OcLEgI_vtZQ&quot;&gt;Skiing Basics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrWL_sO2ox0&quot;&gt;Snowplow Technique&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_yfFGDuJ2g0&quot;&gt;Turning and Carving&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/skii</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/skii</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Breaking Free from Expectations Changed My Life?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only true wisdom is in knowing you know nothing.”&lt;/em&gt; - Socrates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In ancient Greece, a man named Socrates roamed the streets of Athens, engaging in conversations that challenged the very foundations of societal norms and expectations. His relentless questioning led him to the understanding that true wisdom comes from recognizing one’s own ignorance. This profound insight resonates deeply with my own journey of breaking free from predefined boundaries and societal expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, as I sat alone, contemplating the rigid confines of my life, I reflected on the transformative experiences I had while traveling. Each journey exposed me to diverse perspectives and ideas, breaking me out of my bubble. Meeting countless people from different walks of life, I began to question everything and embrace uncertainty. These encounters sparked a flame within me, making me realize that the walls I had built around myself were not real—they were constructs of my own making, influenced by societal norms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-crisis-of-existence&quot;&gt;The Crisis of Existence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-descent-into-meaninglessness&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Descent into Meaninglessness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking free from societal expectations led me into an existential crisis. As I questioned the meaning of life, I found myself grappling with the realization that life, in itself, is inherently meaningless. This thought was both liberating and terrifying. Without a predefined purpose, everything seemed futile. I felt lost and demotivated, as if I were adrift in an endless sea without a compass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Man is condemned to be free; because once thrown into the world, he is responsible for everything he does.”&lt;/em&gt; - Jean-Paul Sartre&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sartre’s words echoed in my mind, emphasizing the burden of freedom. Without external guidance, I was responsible for creating my own meaning. This newfound freedom felt like a heavy weight, dragging me down into a spiral of despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-path-to-self-creation&quot;&gt;The Path to Self-Creation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;embracing-self-awareness&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embracing Self-Awareness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the depths of my crisis, I stumbled upon the concept of self-awareness. I began documenting my thoughts and feelings daily, practicing mindfulness, and reflecting on my actions. This process of self-examination allowed me to understand that purpose and passion are not prebuilt constructs; they are created through our actions and choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The unexamined life is not worth living.”&lt;/em&gt; - Socrates&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote became my mantra as I delved deeper into self-awareness. I realized that true fulfillment comes from within, not from external validation or societal expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-my-own-path&quot;&gt;Creating My Own Path&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this newfound understanding, I started to carve out a path that was uniquely mine. I set goals that resonated with my values and passions, focusing on activities that brought me joy and fulfillment. This approach led to a sense of ownership and pride in my achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dedicated myself to constant physical improvement, recognizing the importance of maintaining a healthy body to support a healthy mind. I also pursued various forms of freedom—psychological, financial, economic, and social. These goals were not just end destinations but part of a never-ending process of growth and self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is not in the stars to hold our destiny but in ourselves.”&lt;/em&gt; - William Shakespeare&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shakespeare’s words reminded me that I am the architect of my own destiny. By setting my own goals and creating a life that aligns with my values, I found a sense of purpose and direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-process-and-fulfillment&quot;&gt;The Power of Process and Fulfillment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;falling-in-love-with-the-journey&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Falling in Love with the Journey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continued on this path, I discovered the secret to consistency: the power of awareness of the values my goals would bring. By focusing on the process rather than the outcome, I found joy in the journey itself. Each step forward, no matter how small, brought a sense of accomplishment and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Success is not the key to happiness. Happiness is the key to success. If you love what you are doing, you will be successful.”&lt;/em&gt; - Albert Schweitzer&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schweitzer’s insight perfectly encapsulated my experience. By loving the process and finding happiness in the present moment, I was able to maintain my motivation and stay on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-takeaways&quot;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questioning Societal Expectations&lt;/strong&gt;: Breaking free from predefined boundaries can lead to an existential crisis, but it is a necessary step towards self-discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating Your Own Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Purpose and passion are not prebuilt; they are created through our actions and choices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: Practicing self-awareness and mindfulness helps in understanding one’s true desires and values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Joy of the Process&lt;/strong&gt;: Focusing on the journey rather than the outcome brings fulfillment and motivation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Growth&lt;/strong&gt;: Constantly setting and pursuing personal goals leads to a sense of purpose and direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my journey from predefined boundaries to a life of freedom and self-creation, I have learned that true fulfillment comes from within. By questioning societal expectations and embracing self-awareness, I found a path that is uniquely mine. The process of growth and self-discovery is never-ending, and I am grateful for the sense of purpose and fulfillment it brings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only limit to our realization of tomorrow is our doubts of today.”&lt;/em&gt; - Franklin D. Roosevelt&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roosevelt’s words remind us that the only barriers to our future success are the doubts we hold today. By embracing our freedom and creating our own path, we can overcome these doubts and achieve true fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean-Paul_Sartre&quot;&gt;Jean-Paul Sartre - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socrates&quot;&gt;Socrates - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Shakespeare&quot;&gt;William Shakespeare - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Schweitzer&quot;&gt;Albert Schweitzer - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franklin_D._Roosevelt&quot;&gt;Franklin D. Roosevelt - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/freedom</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/freedom</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>perspective</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why do i listen to the music?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Without music, life would be a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;― Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my last trip to Himachal, I got involved in a massive argument about playing loud music in public. One of my friends shared their perspective on the kind of music I was listening to, questioning why it had no lyrics, no classical instruments, and was mostly beats and electronic sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They argued that it wasn’t real music and expressed disappointment in how Gen Z isn’t listening to what they consider actual music but instead to these types of sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event made me think more about my relationship with the type of music I’m listening to and helped me understand it more deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a philosophical perspective, music is a reflection of the human condition. Nietzsche’s assertion, &lt;strong&gt;“Without music, life would be a mistake”&lt;/strong&gt; resonates deeply with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.redd.it/zvkgb6ofldy91.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Music&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music, in its various forms, becomes a mirror reflecting our innermost thoughts, emotions, and existential quests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sounds confusing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain it more deeply and also to dive into my personal relationship history with music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;memories-and-emotions&quot;&gt;Memories and Emotions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt that a certain type of music can trigger memories from the past, evoking nostalgic moments? I’m sure everyone has experienced this at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been deep in problem-solving mode, totally focused, and then suddenly you notice the crazy intense music playing in the background? You’re like, &lt;em&gt;“Wow, this is awesome, I need to add this to my playlist”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that national anthems and patriotic songs can make us feel a deep sense of pride and loyalty to our country. At the same time, devotional songs can lift you up spiritually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But have you ever wondered why these songs evoke such strong emotions?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What makes them so special that they can trigger these feelings?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These moments, deeply embedded in our memories, reveal the timeless and universal power of music to touch our hearts and souls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-awakening&quot;&gt;The Awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, my taste in music was pretty basic. I loved classical Bollywood hits, Top chart songs, and Chill lo-fi tunes, all in my own little bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I avoided anything too intense because it usually gave me headaches or just didn’t resonate with me and that was totally fine by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, over time, diving deep into philosophical questions, experiencing different perspectives, traveling a lot, hanging out with friends who listen to diverse genres of music, and trying new experiences opened my senses to a new dimension of sound. Over the period, I could feel the energy and emotion behind every note and rhythm, &lt;strong&gt;that’s when I truly connected with music.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music, at that moment, became more than just sound. It was an experience, a way to connect with myself and express our unspoken emotions. It didn’t need words or traditional instruments, it was powerful in its simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shift led me to understand the diverse meanings and creations of music, allowing me to use it as a personal tool for various aspects of my life : be it &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;self discovery, workouts, focus, or mood management&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philosophers have long contemplated the role of music in human life. Nietzsche, who famously declared that “Without music, life would be a mistake” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:nietzsche&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:nietzsche&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; saw music as an essential force that connected us to our deepest emotions and highest aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nietzsche believed that music had the power to transcend the mundane, allowing us to tap into a more profound sense of purpose and potential.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I started using music for my personal growth. It helps me stay consistent with workouts, push my limits, face fears and challenges, and connect deeply with myself. I’ll dive into this more in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The philosopher Arthur Schopenhauer &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:schopenhauer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:schopenhauer&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; also spoke of music as a universal language that could convey the essence of life’s struggles and triumphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For Schopenhauer&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:schopenhauer:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:schopenhauer&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, music was a direct expression of the world’s will , a force that drives all existence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Through music, we encounter this will and, in turn, are inspired to push beyond our limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A friend once put it perfectly that techno music is like this abstract form of art. &lt;strong&gt;There are no lyrics to tell you what it’s about or how to feel, so you’re left to interpret it in your own way&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s like staring at a painting with no clear subject, you can’t always explain it, but you &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; something, and that’s the beauty of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-experience&quot;&gt;Personal Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have been listening to music extensively for the last 2 years. Some of the major things I’ve noticed are:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose Fuel&lt;/strong&gt;: Music reignites the passion, it’s an tool to keep my desires burning bright and acts as a constant reminder of my goals, pushing me forward when the path gets tough.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Existential Awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: There’s a unique sensation of being truly alive when you’re lost in music. It heightens your awareness of the present moment, making you feel connected to your existence in a profound way.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soul Healer&lt;/strong&gt;: Music has an almost magical ability to mend my soul. It reaches depths that words often can’t, providing solace and comfort during the hardest times.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Booster&lt;/strong&gt;: Whenever feeling drained, using music as your recharge button. A powerful beat or a soothing melody to rejuvenate the spirit, giving me the strength to carry on.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mood Magic&lt;/strong&gt;: music works is like a switch that can instantly change your emotional state. Whether you need a boost of energy, a moment of calm, or a surge of inspiration, the right tune can transport you there.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I’ve noticed that when you start linking music to your experiences, the magic really starts to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have those nostalgic moments with songs that remind us of the past. But things get even more interesting when music becomes tied to a long-term goal or process you’re working on. &lt;em&gt;That music then becomes part of your journey towards achieving that goal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Instance, I began playing the same kind of music I loved, over and over, for specific situations, like my workouts at the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There was this one DJ’s concert on YouTube that I always played. Usually, I’d get bored of a song if I overplayed it, but this time was different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The more I listened, the deeper my connection with that music grew.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I ended up playing the same 1-hour-and-30-minute concert for my entire gym sessions &lt;strong&gt;throughout the year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now, listening to the same music again during your low points triggers that state of mind to push forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that the music became linked to my workout routines, helping me hit my targets and making the overall experience more intense, meaningful and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For instance, when doing self-discovery, journaling , brainstorming or developing new ideas, I turn to Hozho’s &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSNcXegRhcE&quot;&gt;DJ Mix 03 (Live @ Jardins Efémeros, Viseu)&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;. This melodic dark music inspires me and &lt;strong&gt;helps me channel my desires into actionable plans.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music speaks to our inner selves, tapping into what makes life meaningful. It pushes us to make every moment count, urging to strive harder, push past boundaries, and achieve what once thought was impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The beats, lyrics, and rhythms resonated with something deep within me, pushing me to keep going, to push harder, to test and eventually break my limits.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In his philosophy, Nietzsche&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:nietzsche:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:nietzsche&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; often emphasized the importance of embracing life in all its complexity, including its joys and sufferings.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Music, with its ability to evoke and transform emotions, serves as a powerful tool for this embrace. It allows us to feel deeply, to connect with others, and to find meaning even in the face of life’s most challenging moments.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1MobY_vR7-g&quot;&gt;Boris Brejcha at Arènes de Nîmes, in France for Cercle&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt; is a minimal techno concert that fuels my workouts. This music pumps me up, turning what could be a monotonous routine into an exhilarating experience. The repetitive beats and &lt;strong&gt;intense energy make me feel like I’m dancing in a club rather than exercising in a gym.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Every day in the gym, I play this kind of music for the whole past year and visualize myself hiking, running over stones, reaching the top, dancing, and vibing to the music.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When I feel the music during a hike, it’s like a rush of inspiration and euphoria. It makes me feel truly alive and aware of my own existence, and it fills me with pride for all the effort I’ve put in to get there.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This music always reminds me to get out of the comfort zone, that’s exactly where I rediscovered myself, that’s after all, I am capable of things I thought I didn’t have in me.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RvRhUHTV_8k&quot;&gt;Ben Böhmer live above Cappadocia in Turkey for Cercle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a melodic house music set is like a painkiller for me. It relaxes me, keeps me present in the moment, and helps me manifest my desires.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I listen to this music during flow activities that don’t need much effort, like when I’m doing something calm and relaxing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s like finally reaching the top of the mountain you’ve always dreamed of, feeling that pure happiness and peace of mind. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Healing through music is another profound aspect I’ve experienced. Carbon Based Lifeforms’ &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SD6hsVJQtiY?si=cQz1iO9_RS7GBhXJ&quot;&gt;Live at Ozora Festival 2017&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt; is a psy-ambient set that I use to relax and find stillness. The soothing melodies and ambient sounds help calm my mind, reduce stress, and promote a sense of peace.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The concept of music as a healing tool is not new. Throughout history, various cultures have used music to soothe the mind and body.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ancient Greeks, for example, believed in the therapeutic power of music and used it to treat mental and physical ailments.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similarly, indigenous cultures around the world have incorporated music into their healing rituals, recognizing its ability to restore harmony and well-being.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve been using &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Brain.fm&quot;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; music for about a year now, mostly for recharging during work:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Waking up early, doing workouts, handling home stuff, then tackling work and meetings all of this can leave me feeling tired by the afternoon and craving a nap.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I don’t take naps for the recharge, instead, I just lay down on the bed and listen to Brain.fm for 15-20 mins. It helps recharge my energy to start working again.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s been a good alternative to coffee for now :D.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/imgs/inline/spotify.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;spotify&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music, for me, is no longer just about the instruments or the lyrics, it’s about the feelings it evokes.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s about the memories it brings back and the emotions it stirs. Whether it’s the classical symphonies my parents used to play on Sunday mornings or the electronic tracks I now prefer, music has always been a constant companion, reflecting my journey and my growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve been on a musical adventure on Spotify, always on the hunt for new genres, artists, and unique sounds. It’s amazing how discovering fresh tunes can take you on unexpected journeys and open up new horizons. Music really has this incredible ability to change your mood and mindset, don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, When visiting a new place, it can be worthwhile to take in some fresh music and create a lasting memory and emotional association with the location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone also described this to me well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are embedded in the music, as if music and you were one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/imgs/inline/techno.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;found this in dharamkot&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;role-of-music-in-manifestation-and-visualization&quot;&gt;Role of Music in Manifestation and Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manifestation and visualization are powerful techniques that involve using the mind to create and attract desired outcomes. Music can play a significant role in enhancing these practices by creating an emotional and mental state conducive to manifestation. By selecting music that resonates with our goals and desires, we can amplify our intentions and bring them to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, when I visualize achieving a personal goal, I choose music that evokes the emotions associated with that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I’m visualizing success and achievement, I listen to uplifting and triumphant music that fills me with a sense of confidence and empowerment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I’m visualizing relaxation and inner peace, I choose calming and soothing music that fosters a sense of serenity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to using music for manifestation is to select tracks that align with the emotions and mental states you wish to cultivate. By immersing yourself in music that resonates with your intentions, you can create a powerful connection between your mind and your goals, making it easier to manifest your desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always felt a deep connection with music, and I’ve started using it intentionally to alter my brain’s beta waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My plan involves listening to binaural beats and other specialized tracks repeatedly until my brain becomes accustomed to them. Then, I switch to new tracks to further enhance my cognitive abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tools like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brain.fm/&quot;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and Spotify’s beta waves playlists are excellent resources for this practice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-science-behind-music-and-the-brain&quot;&gt;The Science Behind Music and the Brain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has shown that listening to music releases dopamine&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Dopamine&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Dopamine&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the neurotransmitter associated with pleasure and reward. This chemical reaction can enhance our mood, increase our motivation, and even reduce the perception of pain. This explains why athletes often rely on high-energy music to boost their performance during training and competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it’s fascinating to note that different types of music can activate different regions of the brain. For example, rhythmic music engages the motor cortex, which is responsible for movement and coordination. On the other hand, melodic and harmonic music stimulates the auditory cortex, which processes sound. This explains why certain types of music can enhance physical performance, while others can promote relaxation and mental clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Binaural beats, in particular, have gained popularity for their ability to influence brainwave patterns&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Binaural&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Binaural&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. These beats consist of two slightly different frequencies played in each ear, creating a perceived third frequency that corresponds to specific brainwave states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, binaural beats in the delta frequency range (1-4 Hz) can induce deep relaxation and sleep, while those in the beta frequency range (13-30 Hz) can enhance focus and concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started using it intentionally to alter my brain’s beta waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My plan involves listening to binaural beats and other specialized tracks repeatedly until my brain becomes accustomed to them. Then, I switch to new tracks to further enhance my cognitive abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brain.fm/&quot;&gt;Brain.fm&lt;/a&gt; and Spotify’s beta waves playlists are excellent resources for this practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-words&quot;&gt;Closing Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Overstimulation :&lt;/strong&gt; “Anything you consume beyond its threshold will eventually consume you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when my friend criticized my choice in music, it made me realize that everyone’s musical journey is unique. What might seem like noise to one person can be a lifeline to another. And for me, those electronic beats are more than just sounds, they’re a testament to my past, present, and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Again, music is a personal choice and depends on the individual.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone may use it one way or another.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The whole purpose of this article is to share my own experience and relationship with music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music, for me, has evolved from being just a source of entertainment to a profound tool for self-exploration and growth. It’s not just about what you hear; it’s about what you feel and how it shapes your journey. So next time you plug in your earphones, think about what you’re really listening to and how it might be shaping your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Music can change the world because it can change people.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:Bono&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:Bono&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;” - Bono&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hozho. (2021). &lt;strong&gt;DJ Mix 03 (Live @ Jardins Efémeros, Viseu)&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSNcXegRhcE&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brejcha, B. (2020). &lt;strong&gt;Boris Brejcha at Arènes de Nîmes, in France for Cercle&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1MobY_vR7-g&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Böhmer, B. (2021). &lt;strong&gt;Ben Böhmer live above Cappadocia in Turkey for Cercle&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RvRhUHTV_8k&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carbon Based Lifeforms. (2017). &lt;strong&gt;Live at Ozora Festival 2017&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SD6hsVJQtiY?si=cQz1iO9_RS7GBhXJ&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:nietzsche&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Nietzsche, F. (1889). &lt;em&gt;Twilight of the Idols&lt;/em&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/52263&quot;&gt;Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:nietzsche&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:nietzsche:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:schopenhauer&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Schopenhauer, A. (1818). &lt;em&gt;The World as Will and Representation&lt;/em&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/38427&quot;&gt;Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:schopenhauer&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:schopenhauer:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Dopamine&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Research on Music and Dopamine: Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12374491/&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Dopamine&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Binaural&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Research on Binaural Beats: Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28532772/&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Binaural&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:Bono&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bono. (1983). &lt;strong&gt;Quote&lt;/strong&gt;. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/bono_138767&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:Bono&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 03:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/music</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/music</guid>
        
        <category>experience</category>
        
        <category>perspective</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
